Mohammed Mahmoud



+966502669168 | mohammedjrt@gmail.com | Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

Summary

Highly disciplined and enthusiastic individual with a wealth of diverse experiences. Meticulous and precise in every assigned task. Thrives under pressure and remains committed and responsible in crisis situations or high-stress environments. Strong interpersonal skills enable effective relationship building and communication. Fast learner with knowledge in dispensing protocols, inventory management, and regulatory restrictions. Fluent in Arabic and excellent in English, possessing strong language skills for effective communication with diverse individuals.

Experience

Dr. Soliman Fakeeh Hospital | Jeddah, Saudi Arabia Pharmacy Intern | 09/2024 - 11/2024

- Prepared packaging and labels for prescriptions, verifying accuracy of dosage, side effects, interactions, and refill instructions.
- Used pharmacy software to enter prescription and insurance information.
- Counseled patients on new medications and OTC products.
- · Perform numerous extemporaneous compounding.
- Performed technical processes required to dispense medications to patients.
- Reconstituted numerous I.V medicine in the I.V room.

Dr. Samir Abbas Hospital | Jeddah, Saudi Arabia Pharmacy Intern | 08/2024 - 09/2024

- Read and understood hospital's pharmacy department policies and procedures.
- Experienced in documenting and managing narcotic and controlled medications through the Sehhaty and Raqeeb platforms.
- Educated patients on possible drug interactions, potential side effects, and optimal methods of administration.

AlFouaad Specialized Hospital | Khartoum, Sudan Hospital Pharmacist | 07/2022 - 03/2023

- Assisted in the processing of insurance claims and coordinated with healthcare providers to resolve any coverage issues, ensuring timely medication delivery to patients.
- · Managed inventory levels and ordered medications and supplies as needed, optimizing stock levels and reducing waste.
- Collaborated with healthcare providers to review and optimize medication therapy plans for patients with complex medical conditions.
- Counseled patients on medication usage, potential side effects, and drug interactions to promote safe and effective treatment outcomes.
- · Verified safety and accuracy of physician orders.

Brown Pharmacy | Khartoum, Sudan Pharmacist | 03/2022 - 08/2022

- Supported manager in streamlining order and inventory management processes.
- Verified accuracy of received goods by meticulously inspecting quantity and type.
- Maintained the pharmacy in a clean and orderly manner to uphold a professional appearance.
- Consistently achieved and surpassed sales targets, maintaining an outstanding track record.
- Ensured accurate and timely dispensing of prescription medicines to the public.
- · Made critical decisions concerning pharmacy inventory and effectively managed the drug registry.

Skills

Effective Decision-making skills, Communication skills, Time management and organizational skills., Pharmaceutical knowledge in medication management., Knowledge of MOH's Raqeeb, Sehati platforms, Patients Counseling, Knowledge of healthcare regulations and compliance, Ability to work in a team, Outstanding customer service, Confidentiality, Patient Counseling, Drug Therapy Management, Knowledge in medication administration and dispensing, Time Management, Teamwork

Education



University of Gezira | Wad Medani, Sudan Pharmacy | 06/2021

CGPA: 3.26

Certificates

SCFH Pharmacy Licence, Raqeeb Training Course

Awards

Author of a scientific article. https://shorturl.at/xoeer, present two abstract on international scientific conference